Guide to the First Baptist Church in Pierrepont Street records 2011.021
Brooklyn Historical Society
- Series 6: Bible School
  - Bible School Constitution, 1911 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Members, circa 1912-1924 (Box 34)
  - Chinese Bible School, circa 1915, 1932 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Members, circa 1916-1924 (Box 35)
  - Minutes, 1916-1940 (Box 32)
  - Expenses, 1916-1936 (Box 33)
  - Bulletins, 1918-1919, 1921 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Rally Day Flyer, 1919 (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Members, circa 1919-1920 (Box 36)
  - Treasurer's Reports, 1923-1939 (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Senior Treasury Book, 1933-1951 (Box 33)
  - Minutes, 1940-1963 (Box 32)
  - Senior Treasury, 1943-1952 (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Senior Young People's Society Articles, 1944 (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - Bible School Attendance, circa 1945 (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - Girl Scouts, Troop 2-442, 1946-1949 (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - Committees List, 1949 (Box 31, Folder 16)
  - Bible School Teacher's Covenant, circa 1950 (Box 31, Folder 17)
  - Anniversary Parades, 1958-1959 (Box 31, Folder 18)
  - Nominating Committee, 1952-1959 (Box 31, Folder 19)
  - Home Department Report, 1959 (Box 31, Folder 20)
  - Cradle Roll Report, 1959 (Box 31, Folder 21)
  - Nursery School Report, 1983 (Box 31, Folder 22)
- Series 7: Church Publications and Books
  Materials created for Church anniversaries are housed in sub-series 1.2. Materials created for the music department, including programs and flyers, are held in series 5.
  - Sub-series 7.1: Orders of Service and Calendars
    - Calendar, Oversize, 1876 (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - Orders of Service and Calendars, 1889-1895 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Orders of Service and Calendars, 1903-1919 (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Orders of Service and Calendars, 1920-1929 (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - Orders of Service and Calendars, 1922-1925 (Box 37)
    - Orders of Service and Calendars, 1930-1939 (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - Orders of Service and Calendars, 1930-1935 (Box 38)
    - Orders of Service and Calendars, 1936-1941 (Box 38)
    - Orders of Service and Calendars, 1940-1949 (Box 39, Folder 1-2)
    - Orders of Service and Calendars, 1950-1959 (Box 39, Folder 3-4)
    - Orders of Service and Calendars, 1960-1969 (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Orders of Service and Calendars, 1960-1969 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Orders of Service and Calendars, 1970-1977 (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Orders of Service and Calendars, 1980-1989 (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Orders of Service and Calendars, 1990-1999 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Sub-series 7.2: Manuals and Newsletters
    - Church Manuals, 1874, 1920-1921 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - Baptist Temple Monthly, 1985-1998 (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Sub-series 7.3: Advertisements and Mailers
    - Flyers and Brochures, 1921-2001 (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - Poster, circa 1970 (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - Postcards, circa 1980 (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - Printing Orders, 1940 (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - Poster Mockups, circa 1980-1990 (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Sub-series 7.4: Books
    - Poetry by Rev. James McGinlay, 1953-1955 (Box 40, Folder 10)
    - The Birthday of Souls, Rev. James McGinlay, 1938 (Box 40)
    - Heaven's Jewelry, Rev. James McGinlay, 1946 (Box 40)
    - The Standard Manual for Baptist Churches, 1903 (Box 41)
    - The Marble Collegiate Church, 1954 (Box 41)
    - Organized Sunday School Work in America 1905-1908 (Box 41)
    - The Psalter. First Baptist Church in Pierrepont Street, 1883 (Box 41)
    - Modernism. A Revolt Against Christianity. A Foe to Good Government, 1924 (Box 41)
    - The Necessity of Declaring War on Modernism, 1925 (Box 41)
    - The Farewell Sermon of Dr. Harry Emerson Fosdick to The First Presbyterian Church of New York, 1925 (Box 41)
    - The Gospel Witness, Volume 5, Number 3, 1925 (Box 41)
    - Bible, 1846 (Box 45)
- Series 8: Clippings and Scrapbooks
  - Clippings, 1917-2001 (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Press Releases, 1937, 1988 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Clippings Scrapbook, 1927-1955 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Clippings Scrapbook, circa 1941-1954 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook, 1945 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Clippings Scrapbook, 1963-1965 (Box 37, Folder 4)
- Series 9: Administrative Records and Correspondence
  - Payments and Donations, 1895-1946 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Other Churches, 1897 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Financial Notes and Reports, Various, 1911-1993 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Burials and Cemetery Plots, 1913-1936 (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Church Collection Envelopes and Cards, circa 1915-1950 (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Personnel, circa 1920-1989 (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Weather Reports, 1939-1956 (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Church Visitor Materials, 1945-1990 (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Missionary Workers of New York, Minutes and Correspondence, 1947-1975 (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Central Explorer's Shares, circa 1954 (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - Conservative Baptist Association of America, 1956-1999 (Box 42, Folder 10)
  - Lord of Life, Radio Transcript, 1960 (Box 42, Folder 11)
  - Brooklyn History Fair, 1994-1995 (Box 42, Folder 12)
  - Contacts and Mailing List, circa 1995 (Box 42, Folder 13)
  - Long Island Baptist Association Minutes, 1916-1931 (Box 42, Folder 14)
  - Long Island Baptist Association Minutes, 1932-1943 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Long Island Baptist Association Minutes, 1944-1947 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, General, 1844, 1893-2002 (Box 43, Folder 3-4)
  - Correspondence, General, 1942-1953 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, World War II, 1943-1945 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Bequest and Estate Documents, 1920-1945 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Letters of Dismission to First Baptist Church, 1841-1850 (Box 44, Folder 3-4)
- Series 10: Visual Materials
  - Sub-series 10.1: Photographs and Prints
    - People, circa 1874-2000 (Box 49, Binder 1)
    - People, Oversize, circa 1905-2000 (Box 48, Folder 5-7)
    - People, Oversize, circa 1890-1930 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - People, Oversize, circa 1927-1944 (Folder Flat File)
    - Exteriors, circa 1850-2000 (Box 49, Binder 2)
    - Exterior, circa 1910 (Box 52)
    - Exteriors, Oversize, circa 1890-1921 (Box 48, Folder 8)
    - Interiors, circa 1948-2000 (Box 49, Binder 2)
    - Interiors, Oversize, circa 1905-1948 (Box 48, Folder 9)
    - Drawings and Prints, 1890-1940 (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Sub-series 10.2: Paintings
    - Portrait of Rev. Cortland Meyers, circa 1920 (Box 50)
- Series 11: Artifacts
  - Silver Plate Presented by Greenwood Baptist Church, 1918 (Box 51)
  - Inter-Patrol Trophy for Boy Scout Troop 63, 1925-1926 (Box 51)
  - Plaque Dedicated to Wilson and Maria Marikle, 1957 (Box 51)
  - Stamp, circa 1980 (Box 51)